How to search for, you know, encircle Lincoln List.
Consider this link list that contains four notes.
The first one is for containing note that have a value of 400.
The second 130 200 and third at the fourth is containing data for 300, and the other is four thousand
twenty four, 1024, two thousand twenty four and three thousand twenty four, respectively.
The last one since it is Circle Link, at least the last one points and the reference to the first note.
So this this is the head of the Circle linkage list.
And to search for a list, a circle linked list, we move the head and we read the value inside the
note.
OK?
Later on, we will see how to print and implement everything and the Java and how to print the values
of this note.
And while working in the real exercises.
So don't worry, we are going to make these and that real life and real programs.
We have have and we are searching for 200, so this example, we are searching for the value of hundred.
So the first one at the beginning, we create a temporary value and temporary difference that points.
That's exactly at that first point.
And the first note and how to get the first note by referring it as equal to had so stamp equal to two
hundred.
And it is equal to their head.
So this is the key that we are searching for, which is to hunt with search check two hundred equal
to two 400.
No.
So it will mark it as X and as it does not equal and moves to the next one, then this 200 compares.
This temporary value compares to 100 was 100.
If they are equal, then it will return the value.
But this is not the case.
It is not equal.
It moves to the next one.
So 200 equal to the 200 that is contained in the note.
Yes.
So this is the case, and it returns the the reference and returns that index of this note that it is
contained or it returns boolean like true or false if it is contained or not, according to the returning
type of the of the method that we have created.
So this is based on the returning type of the method that we have created.
Consider another example.
This is the linked list, the same Lincoln list, and we are searching for the value of 500.
The first one checked 500 equal to 400.
No.
It moves to the next 500 equal to 100.
It's move.
It moves to their next 500 equal to 200.
No.
It moves to the next note and 500 equal to 300.
But 300.
This note referred to the head.
Then we have reached the end of that link at last.
Therefore, we stopped searching and return false.
We didn't find the 500 and so along that notes inside this link at list how to implement the search
and search method inside the Circle Link unless we create any search and key that key as a perimeter
and start.
If had equal equal to null, then return minus one.
If it is referring to us as an empty list, then return minus one struct note stamp equal to had to
create a new temporary value and variable equal to the head, pointing to the same node as the had to
refer.
And this is referred for us as the start of the linked list do and do.
While this is the loop that we enter and start checking, if temp data equal equal to the key, then
return one stamp equal temp.
Not next, so move then time.
According to this loop, check in by checking if it is equal to their data or not.
Tempest, what if what the heck?
So move along that note until you reach them equal equal to the hat?
No.
Let's see another case if the.
That same, the same method, but we didn't have.
The key found inside the link, at least if we search for 500, we see this example 500 is not a contained
in the first, second, third note and the fourth note.
And we have reached the end.
This is the trick behind the circular link at least and searching investigating how to know that we
have reached the end.
If attempt, if this is equal to the head.
If we go back to the had sent.
So we have reached the end of the circle learning curve list and we didn't find anything that we are
searching for.
We didn't find the value inside the notes, so it were returned minus one, according to that, a returning
type, which is end of that search method.
Then complexity, time, complexity would be best cases of one.
So finding the note at the beginning.
So consider in for this example look at these notes for nuts.
The first note contains 400 if we are searching for 400, so it will find the 400 in the first note
and it contains and coast time complexity would be one.
While if we are searching along the list for like 500 and we didn't find it, so we go through all the
elements, all the notes.
Therefore, the time complexity would be of and depending on the number of the nodes that we have in
that list.
So this is the trick behind the circular learning could list and the searching.